<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learning on Josef Spjut</title>
    <link>http://josef.spjut.me/tags/learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Learning on Josef Spjut</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Josef Spjut</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/learning/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Student-run Class Sessions</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/teaching/2014/02/07/student-run-class-sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/teaching/2014/02/07/student-run-class-sessions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This semester I am teaching a project-based class that has almost no
formal instruction by the professor. Instead of providing close
direction, I am attempting to give the students more autonomy and
control over their learning and the things they will get out of the
class.
This presents a number of difficulties, and I plan to discuss them as
the semester proceeds.
Today, I&amp;rsquo;d like to say something about student-run class sessions,
which will happen for the first time in my class next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In planning for these class sessions, I&amp;rsquo;ve attempted to make it easy
for students to provide good objectives and learning opportunities for
each other.
Students have about 8 minutes for their presentations, and they are
required to introduce some technical component, and then provide at
least one good example of how that component might be used for their
project or another project within the scope of the class.
8 minutes is a very short time to get through so much technical
detail, but my hope is that they will learn how to distill the
valuable information they gain into bite-sized chunks that are easy
for others to digest and reuse.
During these student-run presentations, I plan to keep things on track
by recommending they continue on topic and get through both the
introduction to the component and a concrete example.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
