<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on Josef Spjut</title>
    <link>http://josef.spjut.me/categories/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on Josef Spjut</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Josef Spjut</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://josef.spjut.me/categories/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Jetson TK1 First Steps</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2014/05/20/jetson-tk1-first-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2014/05/20/jetson-tk1-first-steps/</guid>
      <description>I recently received my Jetson TK1 Development Board, which I&amp;rsquo;m evaluating for potential use in an embedded systems course next Spring. This board is attractive to me because it has a high-end quad core ARM A15 processor as well as a high-end mobile GPU with support for the latest OpenGL and CUDA development environments. This post is going to serve as a way for me to record the things needed to set up the device in the first place, and hopefully more posts will follow as I manage to develop some examples on the board that will hopefully turn into lab assignments for the class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animated GIFs from Movies</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2014/01/25/animated-gifs-from-movies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2014/01/25/animated-gifs-from-movies/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve often wanted to be able to make animated gifs of things. I have also been interested in simple programmatic video editing from time to time, particularly for animating a series of still frames from images rendered by my graphics architecture simulations. Today on reddit, I came across this blog post that describes a sequence of ways to use the MoviePy library to generate animated gifs. It looks like exactly the kind of solution I want since I like to use python whenever possible for simple things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting python style print in C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2013/12/12/interesting-python-style-print-in-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2013/12/12/interesting-python-style-print-in-c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I came across a really interesting piece of C++ code today hidden in
this &lt;a href=&#34;http://madebyevan.com/obscure-cpp-features/?viksra&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;list of obscure C++
features&lt;/a&gt;.
It includes an implementation of some of the &lt;code&gt;print&lt;/code&gt; syntax
functionality of python 2 implemented in C++.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the code (copied here, but I&amp;rsquo;m not the original author):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easiest Development Job Ever</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2013/09/25/easiest-development-job-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2013/09/25/easiest-development-job-ever/</guid>
      <description>Today I came across a blog post from a developer who describes a project he worked on that failed spectacularly. This project was a web database query to sort real estate brokers for an insurance company. If you want to see the results of the project in the way the original author intended, then you should visit the link above. It turns out that the insurance company provides the contact info of real estate brokers solely to collect a referral fee for that service.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>