<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Josef Spjut</title>
    <link>http://josef.spjut.me/tags/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Josef Spjut</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Josef Spjut</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/research/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Submitting my first article to arXiv</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/research/2014/12/02/submitting-my-first-article-to-arxiv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/research/2014/12/02/submitting-my-first-article-to-arxiv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I submitted a technical report done by my students over the last academic year.
It took a while to get the write-up to the level of quality that I felt good about submitting it,
but now that it&amp;rsquo;s there, I figured I should push it out.
I used &lt;a href=&#34;http://arxiv.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;arXiv&lt;/a&gt; to post it since they make it easy to publish a technical report
while not preventing you from submitting the work to another venue such as a conference or journal
at a later date.
I used Latex to write the paper, and in preparing the submission, there were a
couple modifications I had to make to get it accepted by the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I had to include a line that says &lt;code&gt;\pdfoutput=1&lt;/code&gt; somewhere
in the first 5 lines of the main tex file I submitted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, I had to include the &lt;code&gt;main.bbl&lt;/code&gt; file that was generated
locally as part of my build process.
It appears that they don&amp;rsquo;t actually need the &lt;code&gt;.bib&lt;/code&gt; file and
only care about the &lt;code&gt;.bbl&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, my particular document used a style sheet called &lt;code&gt;jpaper.cls&lt;/code&gt; that
had a strange error with how it includes the &lt;code&gt;hyperref&lt;/code&gt; package.
The relevant lines that I had to comment out are below (comments added):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-latex&#34;&gt;% Link and URL formatting.
%\iftoggle{jp@hyperref}{
%  \RequirePackage{hyperref}
%  \hypersetup{
%    unicode=true,
%    pdfstartview={FitH},
%    colorlinks=true,
%    %citecolor=black,
%    %filecolor=black,
%    %linkcolor=black,
%    %urlcolor=black
% }}{}
%\RequirePackage{url}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I had an issue with figures I included that I think had to do with how
I uploaded all of the source material.
Since I submitted each file separately instead of part of a compressed folder,
the graphics I was trying to include were now a part of the root directory instead
of being present in the &lt;code&gt;graphics&lt;/code&gt; subdirectory that I use locally.
Luckily, there was a straightforward fix that I think I&amp;rsquo;ll include in my future
documents by default because it&amp;rsquo;s much cleaner than what I&amp;rsquo;ve done traditionally.
In the main &lt;code&gt;.tex&lt;/code&gt; file include a line like the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-latex&#34;&gt;% graphics path
\graphicspath{ {./graphics/} }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, instead of including the relative path to everything in the graphics path,
just include the graphics directly as in this example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-latex&#34;&gt;\begin{figure}
\centering
\includegraphics[width=\columnwidth]{PairedCaches}
\caption{Partly shared instruction caches}
\label{fig:paired}
\end{figure}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Design Thoughts</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/game-design/2014/01/14/game-design-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/game-design/2014/01/14/game-design-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking recently about the kinds of things I&amp;rsquo;d like to work
on most during the break from teaching, and I&amp;rsquo;ve decided that I really
want to take a deep look at game design from a theoretical and
practical standpoint.
It seems to me that there could be some need for a more formal and
methodological approach to the design of games than currently exists.
In my experience, game designers (the ones that put the fun into the
game) are hard to find and extremely hard to train.
Smallish tasks like level design can be learned, but even these are
typically only learned by spending a large amount of time practicing
and depend on the intuition of the individuals to be successful.
Coming from my background in computer architecture, and in particular
thinking about the standard text, &amp;ldquo;Computer Architecture: A
Quantitative Approach&amp;rdquo; by Hennessey and Patterson, it occurred to me
that there could exist a game design text with a similar approach and
title.
Quantitative design would not necessarily solve everything that needs
to be done in game design given that so much of the design is itself
artistic expression, but the existence of such a text could greatly
assist in training game designers initially.
My quick search on google for research and writing on this subject has
not turned up much, but there is this
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.academia.edu/2988547/Game_Design_by_Numbers_Instrumental_Play_and_the_Quantitative_Shift_in_the_Digital_Game_Industry&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Recent PhD Thesis&lt;/a&gt;
that I think is probably the most recent related work in this area,
though it is written by a sociologist (not necessarily a bad thing).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to use my blog posts in the category of &amp;ldquo;game design&amp;rdquo; to
brainstorm a bit about how this theoretical book might be organized.
The biggest challenge will be finding a way to quantify the clearly
artistic and qualitative experience that the player enjoys when
playing a game.
The question I need to ask is how to quantify each of the following
essential (or at least helpful) game design features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fun&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;happiness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;human experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;social interaction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;addiction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;monetary impact (both to the player and the developer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;others?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really understanding a lot of these concepts requires a huge amount of
cross-disciplinary work and depends on a better understanding of
social sciences than I currently have.
The question of monetary impact is directly related to business and
economic concerns.
Perhaps the easiest thing to quantify is the amount of time spent on a
particular activity.
However, answering the question of how much time is spent on something
is not entirely useful unless you are aware of the impact that
activity has on the player in terms of most of the other concepts.
If you only take into account time and money when you design a game,
you can easily create a game that will use as much time as a player
has available and deliver the maximum amount of money to the pockets
of the developer, but I do not believe that should be the goal in
designing a game.
A game should be designed to enhance the life experience of the
individual playing that game.
Sure money is necessary to cover the costs of developing, distributing
and marketing a game, but money can also be used as an incentive to
the player.
For instance, I have found that games with a paid barrier to entry
tend to invite a higher caliber of social interaction among players
than those that are free to play.
Higher quality social interaction is certainly beneficial to the life
experience of each participant in that interaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m out of time for today, but I will be returning to these thoughts
again soon. The next entry should be more focussed than these rambling
thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undergraduate Research</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/research/2013/09/19/undergraduated-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/research/2013/09/19/undergraduated-research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last year, I advised 5 undergraduate students on a couple
research projects. One of them included the development of tutorials
and lab assignments for a new class, but didn&amp;rsquo;t have a goal of
publishing an academic paper. This student did a good job, and added
on a persistance of vision display to a combat robot&amp;rsquo;s spinning arm
that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have otherwise been there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other main project involved the rest of my research students.
Three of those students were seniors, and have since graduated and
began working full-time jobs in industry.
However, the research they performed was very good, and we are
currently working on an academic paper that I believe to represent a
significant contribution to the field of cache performance analysis.
In fact one of these former students believes that our methods may be
useful to his current employer where he&amp;rsquo;s involved in a dram caching
layer for a large database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real difficulty I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered in finishing off this paper comes
from the lack of availability from the authors, and the lack of
accountability to me for performing work.
The project took some time to get started last fall, and as a result
we only finished about half of what I had planned for the year.
It seems that student pay is a poor motivator for students that will
be making significantly more based on their course grades.
The students I had doing research for grades seemed much more likely
to try to do what I asked, though one had some serious problems
describing what was missing from that student&amp;rsquo;s knowledge.
The end result was that I could not advise this student effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even after all of the challenges, the goal is to submit the paper in
the next week. Right now it&amp;rsquo;s not even close to complete. Here&amp;rsquo;s
hoping that the (former) students can find the time to complete the
paper.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
