<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Embedded Systems on Josef Spjut</title>
    <link>http://josef.spjut.me/tags/embedded-systems/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Embedded Systems on Josef Spjut</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Josef Spjut</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/embedded-systems/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Jetson TK1 First Steps</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2014/05/20/jetson-tk1-first-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2014/05/20/jetson-tk1-first-steps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently received my &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.nvidia.com/jetson-tk1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jetson TK1 Development
Board&lt;/a&gt;, which I&amp;rsquo;m evaluating
for potential use in an embedded systems course next Spring.
This board is attractive to me because it has a high-end quad core ARM
A15 processor as well as a high-end mobile GPU with support for the
latest OpenGL and CUDA development environments.
This post is going to serve as a way for me to record the things
needed to set up the device in the first place, and hopefully more
posts will follow as I manage to develop some examples on the board
that will hopefully turn into lab assignments for the class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you notice when you plug in the board and turn it on,
is that it boots to an OS without any setup because the built-in flash
has linux on it from the factory.
However, there is no x11 support out of the box.
Well that&amp;rsquo;s not quite true&amp;hellip;
The support is available, but you must &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.download.nvidia.com/embedded/jetson/TK1/README.txt&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;run a script to install the
driver&lt;/a&gt;.
The instructions from the README are copied and inline here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This README file lists instructions on how to install the NVIDIA
Linux driver binary release on your target located in:
${HOME}/NVIDIA-INSTALLER

Step 1)
Change directories into the NVIDIA installation directory:
    cd ${HOME}/NVIDIA-INSTALLER

Step 2)
Run the installer script to extract and install the Linux driver
binary release:
    sudo ./installer.sh

Step 3)
Reboot the system to have the graphical desktop UI come up.

NOTES:
- The installer.sh should only be run once.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More to come&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
