<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Josef Spjut</title>
    <link>http://josef.spjut.me/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Josef Spjut</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Josef Spjut</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://josef.spjut.me/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Phaser Game</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/post/2017/phaser-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 15:14:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/post/2017/phaser-game/</guid>
      <description>In the past few weeks, I decided to spend some of my spare time trying out some new methods for game development. In particular, I thought it would be good to come up with something that would allow me to easily create a networked game for multiple players, and would give me a chance to learn something new. I decided to look into javascript frameworks, and there were a wide variety out there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Notes</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/post/2017/hugo-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 09:49:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/post/2017/hugo-notes/</guid>
      <description>I recently undertook the effort of moving my website from jekyll using jekyll-bootstrap to Hugo and I wanted to record some notes from my efforts. In particular I want to collect a set of useful links that helped me in making the switch.
For what it&amp;rsquo;s worth, I greatly prefer Hugo now that I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten used to it, though there wasn&amp;rsquo;t too much broken about Jekyll.
The most useful thing for developing my site was when I found the academic theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introductory Cache Problem</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/teaching/2015/05/13/an-introductory-cache-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/teaching/2015/05/13/an-introductory-cache-problem/</guid>
      <description>I recently gave a problem on the final in E85. The students didn&amp;rsquo;t do too well on it overall, so I wanted to post the problem and solution in an effort to make more resources available for people learning basic cache behaviors. First of all, I need to introduce the piece of ARM assembly being used since it is the basis for a number of questions.
	FUNC: 0x0044	SUBS R0, R0, #3 0x0048	BLT DONE 0x004C	STR LR, [SP, #-4]!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Submitting my first article to arXiv</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/research/2014/12/02/submitting-my-first-article-to-arxiv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/research/2014/12/02/submitting-my-first-article-to-arxiv/</guid>
      <description>Today I submitted a technical report done by my students over the last academic year. It took a while to get the write-up to the level of quality that I felt good about submitting it, but now that it&amp;rsquo;s there, I figured I should push it out. I used arXiv to post it since they make it easy to publish a technical report while not preventing you from submitting the work to another venue such as a conference or journal at a later date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automount network drives on a Mac</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/osx/2014/09/05/automount-network-drives-on-a-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/osx/2014/09/05/automount-network-drives-on-a-mac/</guid>
      <description>I recently added a network storage device to my home network and decided I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to have to keep reconnecting to the device every time I got home and wanted to use it. I did a little searching and found a tool called ControlPlane that seems ideally suited to solve my issue. ControlPlane is really a tool to detect where you are using things that are already available and allow for automated actions to be taken when you arrive or leave a place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Cardboard compatilbe iOS apps</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/virtual-reality/2014/08/18/google-cardboard-compatilbe-ios-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/virtual-reality/2014/08/18/google-cardboard-compatilbe-ios-apps/</guid>
      <description>I got a Google Cardboard last week at SIGGRAPH and since I don&amp;rsquo;t own an Android phone, I set out to find a way to use my iPhone to try it out. The first thing I noticed is that there were no web pages easily found that mentioned a list of apps that are compatible with it, even without including the magnetic switch for input. What follows is a short list of apps I discovered on my search:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jetson TK1 First Steps</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2014/05/20/jetson-tk1-first-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2014/05/20/jetson-tk1-first-steps/</guid>
      <description>I recently received my Jetson TK1 Development Board, which I&amp;rsquo;m evaluating for potential use in an embedded systems course next Spring. This board is attractive to me because it has a high-end quad core ARM A15 processor as well as a high-end mobile GPU with support for the latest OpenGL and CUDA development environments. This post is going to serve as a way for me to record the things needed to set up the device in the first place, and hopefully more posts will follow as I manage to develop some examples on the board that will hopefully turn into lab assignments for the class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Busy Semester</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/teaching/2014/04/16/a-busy-semester/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/teaching/2014/04/16/a-busy-semester/</guid>
      <description>This semester has been extremely exciting. In particular, E85 has been updated from MIPS to use the ARM v7 instructions set. This has been a good experience for me despite some difficulties and a few moments of intensity where I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure things would come together in time. In doing this, I&amp;rsquo;ve come to learn a lot about the ARM ISA, and I&amp;rsquo;ve decided I like it a lot. In particular, I think it strikes a reasonably good balance between RISC and CISC instructions where there are a couple nice addressing modes for stack manipulation that aren&amp;rsquo;t quite RISC, but are close enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student-run Class Sessions</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/teaching/2014/02/07/student-run-class-sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/teaching/2014/02/07/student-run-class-sessions/</guid>
      <description>This semester I am teaching a project-based class that has almost no formal instruction by the professor. Instead of providing close direction, I am attempting to give the students more autonomy and control over their learning and the things they will get out of the class. This presents a number of difficulties, and I plan to discuss them as the semester proceeds. Today, I&amp;rsquo;d like to say something about student-run class sessions, which will happen for the first time in my class next week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animated GIFs from Movies</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2014/01/25/animated-gifs-from-movies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2014/01/25/animated-gifs-from-movies/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve often wanted to be able to make animated gifs of things. I have also been interested in simple programmatic video editing from time to time, particularly for animating a series of still frames from images rendered by my graphics architecture simulations. Today on reddit, I came across this blog post that describes a sequence of ways to use the MoviePy library to generate animated gifs. It looks like exactly the kind of solution I want since I like to use python whenever possible for simple things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Design Thoughts</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/game-design/2014/01/14/game-design-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/game-design/2014/01/14/game-design-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking recently about the kinds of things I&amp;rsquo;d like to work on most during the break from teaching, and I&amp;rsquo;ve decided that I really want to take a deep look at game design from a theoretical and practical standpoint. It seems to me that there could be some need for a more formal and methodological approach to the design of games than currently exists. In my experience, game designers (the ones that put the fun into the game) are hard to find and extremely hard to train.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Author Affiliations in LaTeX</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/latex/2014/01/03/multiple-author-affiliations-in-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/latex/2014/01/03/multiple-author-affiliations-in-latex/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently had the pleasure of updating a recent journal article submission with my list of affiliations. On the article, there are 5 authors, and among them, I am the only one with different affiliations, though I share the other affiliation with the rest of the authors. After some quick googling on how I should perform this, I came up with the following snippet of code that should have worked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting python style print in C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2013/12/12/interesting-python-style-print-in-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2013/12/12/interesting-python-style-print-in-c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I came across a really interesting piece of C++ code today hidden in
this &lt;a href=&#34;http://madebyevan.com/obscure-cpp-features/?viksra&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;list of obscure C++
features&lt;/a&gt;.
It includes an implementation of some of the &lt;code&gt;print&lt;/code&gt; syntax
functionality of python 2 implemented in C++.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the code (copied here, but I&amp;rsquo;m not the original author):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NVIDIA GameWorks</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/graphics/2013/10/18/nvidia-gameworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/graphics/2013/10/18/nvidia-gameworks/</guid>
      <description>Today, NVIDIA announced a new program to help game developers effectively use NVIDIA hardware called GameWorks. The thing that excites me the most about GameWorks is the inclusion of Optix in a program that directly targets game developers. Optix is a ray tracing environment developed by people I know from my studies at Utah that has previously been used to help develop rendering engines for design and production environments. This recent announcement means that the important global illumination features that work more naturally in ray tracing will be more readily available for game developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musical Projects</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/teaching/2013/10/15/musical-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/teaching/2013/10/15/musical-projects/</guid>
      <description>Today I had the fortunate presence of mind to record videos for a couple of my students&amp;rsquo; lab projects that I found particularly interesting. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll go ahead and embed these videos for anyone interested in watching them. To explain briefly, the assignment was to use assembly programming for the PIC 32 microcontroller to have a speaker produce a song. Optionally, students were allowed to play a song of their choosing after putting that song in the program memory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsive Videos in Jekyll</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/website/2013/10/15/responsive-videos-in-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/website/2013/10/15/responsive-videos-in-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>For my other blog post today, I decided I wanted to embed the youtube videos I recorded earlier. Since the rest of my website is fully responsive now, I thought it would be best to find a way to allow embedded videos to also be responsive to the browser window. This is one of the main reasons I started using bootstrap in the first place, and jekyllbootstrap for my website. Luckily I came across the excellent post Todd Motto made posting his fluidvids.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Thoughts</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/personal/2013/10/07/some-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/personal/2013/10/07/some-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>This weekend I got a chance to spend some time thinking about life and a variety of concerns. My church has a General Conference every 6 months and this last weekend was one such conference. During these conferences the church leaders share their thoughts and give direction and guidance to help people to live better lives where they can contribute more to the church and society at large. As the weekend went on, I shared a couple of quotes from the procedings that stood out to me on my twitter account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FSM vs. English</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/teaching/2013/10/03/fsm-vs-english/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/teaching/2013/10/03/fsm-vs-english/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I managed to put together the in-class demo I discussed previously. In this post I&amp;rsquo;d like to give a brief explanation of what I showed and how it demonstrates the proper use of SystemVerilog to describe a finite state machine (FSM).
What I saw many students doing in their 3rd lab, was to use an English language description of the behavior they wanted that they translated directly to behavioral SystemVerilog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Lecture</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/teaching/2013/10/01/interactive-lecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/teaching/2013/10/01/interactive-lecture/</guid>
      <description>In grading some labs this week, I noticed a trend among my students to create something that was essentially a finite state machine (FSM) without actually explicitly making a finite state machine in their verilog description. Typically a FSM has 3 parts, a state register, next state logic, and output logic. The only part of the FSM that should be sequential logic is the state register while the other parts should be purely combinational logic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easiest Development Job Ever</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2013/09/25/easiest-development-job-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2013/09/25/easiest-development-job-ever/</guid>
      <description>Today I came across a blog post from a developer who describes a project he worked on that failed spectacularly. This project was a web database query to sort real estate brokers for an insurance company. If you want to see the results of the project in the way the original author intended, then you should visit the link above. It turns out that the insurance company provides the contact info of real estate brokers solely to collect a referral fee for that service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Email a Professor</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/teaching/2013/09/23/how-to-email-a-professor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/teaching/2013/09/23/how-to-email-a-professor/</guid>
      <description>Just a quick note on emailing professors. If you are asking for help or corrections on an assignment, you should send those kinds of emails ahead of time. Also, if you expect the professor to have complete knowledge of the problems in the book on the weekend, then you&amp;rsquo;re going to have a bad time. Every semester, I&amp;rsquo;ve had questions about problems in the book, and the student will email me the problem number in question rather than describe what the problem is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPhone 5S Release</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/technology/2013/09/20/iphone-5s-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/technology/2013/09/20/iphone-5s-release/</guid>
      <description>I bought my first iPhone 2 years ago in October of 2011. I got the 5th iPhone then, the one called the iPhone 4S (or force for short). Two years have passed and I was eligible for a subsidized upgrade on the 7th iPhone, which they call iPhone 5S (is that SS or 55?). I decided I wanted to get the new upgrade, so I went ahead and ordered one online just after midnight when they went on sale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undergraduate Research</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/research/2013/09/19/undergraduated-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/research/2013/09/19/undergraduated-research/</guid>
      <description>Over the last year, I advised 5 undergraduate students on a couple research projects. One of them included the development of tutorials and lab assignments for a new class, but didn&amp;rsquo;t have a goal of publishing an academic paper. This student did a good job, and added on a persistance of vision display to a combat robot&amp;rsquo;s spinning arm that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have otherwise been there.
The other main project involved the rest of my research students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jekyll Bootstrap: rake post</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/website/2013/09/18/jekyll-bootstrap-rake-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/website/2013/09/18/jekyll-bootstrap-rake-post/</guid>
      <description>I recently discovered a new feature that comes with Jekyll bootstrap, but I&amp;rsquo;m unsure whether it is only in JB, or if it comes by default with Jekyll. There is a Rakefile (which is sort of like a Makefile, but written in Ruby) that includes a few nice functions. The one I discovered most recently allows you to create a new blog post complete with the YAML frontmatter and the proper file name for Jekyll to do the right thing with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embedded Design</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/teaching/2013/09/17/embedded-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/teaching/2013/09/17/embedded-design/</guid>
      <description>This week I met with each of the students in my MicroPs class and discussed their lab assignment. The first lab assignment was primarily soldering components onto their PCB and verifying that all of the components worked. As part of these lab interviews, I get to ask each student a question about their project to try to test their knowledge. One thing I noticed is that many of the students didn&amp;rsquo;t own their project as fully as I would like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Weeks In</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/teaching/2013/09/12/two-weeks-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/teaching/2013/09/12/two-weeks-in/</guid>
      <description>In my embedded systems class, I decided it would be helpful to start with a review of SystemVerilog to hopefully keep the students from falling into the common pitfalls that come with using hardware description languages to describe hardware. Some important topics I touched on include the &amp;ldquo;proper&amp;rdquo; way to describe a Finite State Machine using SystemVerilog. As a part of that, I made sure to point out the kinds of things that you can do in SystemVerilog to accidentally describe sequential logic when you actually intended for the circuit to be combinational.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Not Have a Life</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/teaching/2013/09/02/how-to-not-have-a-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/teaching/2013/09/02/how-to-not-have-a-life/</guid>
      <description>A couple weeks ago, I received a call asking me to teach an extra class this semester (Fall 2013). This was the result of a last minute change out of my control that required an extra instructor to come in on the class. I decided to say &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo; because I have taught the course before, and I was probably the most natural fit to fill in at the last minute. Unfortunately, this caused my other class to have to change lecture time, and subsequently caused a whole bunch of scheduling issues with many students in the class who were taking classes at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year, New Website</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/website/2013/09/01/new-year-new-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/website/2013/09/01/new-year-new-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I happened across [jekyll-bootstrap][] the other day, and I decided I
should move my website to &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;github.io&lt;/a&gt; after seeing
what &lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;jekyll&lt;/a&gt; can do.
Among my favorite features are the ability to use markdown for web
pages, which allows a reasonably good citation syntax for adding links
to my co-authors.
As an example, the following is the syntax for one paper along with
the citations to my co-authors:
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>