<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on Josef Spjut</title>
    <link>http://josef.spjut.me/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on Josef Spjut</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Josef Spjut</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/technology/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Jetson TK1 First Steps</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2014/05/20/jetson-tk1-first-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2014/05/20/jetson-tk1-first-steps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently received my &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.nvidia.com/jetson-tk1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jetson TK1 Development
Board&lt;/a&gt;, which I&amp;rsquo;m evaluating
for potential use in an embedded systems course next Spring.
This board is attractive to me because it has a high-end quad core ARM
A15 processor as well as a high-end mobile GPU with support for the
latest OpenGL and CUDA development environments.
This post is going to serve as a way for me to record the things
needed to set up the device in the first place, and hopefully more
posts will follow as I manage to develop some examples on the board
that will hopefully turn into lab assignments for the class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you notice when you plug in the board and turn it on,
is that it boots to an OS without any setup because the built-in flash
has linux on it from the factory.
However, there is no x11 support out of the box.
Well that&amp;rsquo;s not quite true&amp;hellip;
The support is available, but you must &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.download.nvidia.com/embedded/jetson/TK1/README.txt&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;run a script to install the
driver&lt;/a&gt;.
The instructions from the README are copied and inline here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This README file lists instructions on how to install the NVIDIA
Linux driver binary release on your target located in:
${HOME}/NVIDIA-INSTALLER

Step 1)
Change directories into the NVIDIA installation directory:
    cd ${HOME}/NVIDIA-INSTALLER

Step 2)
Run the installer script to extract and install the Linux driver
binary release:
    sudo ./installer.sh

Step 3)
Reboot the system to have the graphical desktop UI come up.

NOTES:
- The installer.sh should only be run once.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More to come&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPhone 5S Release</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/technology/2013/09/20/iphone-5s-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/technology/2013/09/20/iphone-5s-release/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I bought my first iPhone 2 years ago in October of 2011.
I got the 5th iPhone then, the one called the iPhone 4S (or &lt;em&gt;force&lt;/em&gt;
for short).
Two years have passed and I was eligible for a subsidized upgrade on
the 7th iPhone, which they call iPhone 5S (is that SS or 55?).
I decided I wanted to get the new upgrade, so I went ahead and ordered
one online just after midnight when they went on sale.
I ordered from Apple&amp;rsquo;s website, but there was no option to select
in-store pick up, which I would have preferred.
Instead, all shipping options suggested that the phone might not be
delivered until October, because it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t ship for 1-3 business
days.
Still, I placed an order to ensure I&amp;rsquo;d have a spot in line in case I
couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a way to get one from the retail store later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I left my house in the morning, I decided to drive past the Apple
store to see if the line was short enough while I was on my way to
work.
What I found was a huge line of people wrapping far around the
building more than an hour before the store was set to open.
I decided that my time would be best spent going to work and
performing my work duties for the day.
After I completed my tasks of the day, I decided I&amp;rsquo;d give the Apple
store another shot, just in case they got another order in.
It turned out that they actually had one left of the exact model I
wanted when I walked in the store to look at them, but someone else
got in the line seconds before I did and got to walk away with the
phone.
However, only 30 minutes later, the store decided to release the other
unclaimed phones that were reserved by people earlier in the day.
This included the phone that I got to buy and take home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess the moral of the story is to buy things because that is one
way to get things.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
