<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on Josef Spjut</title>
    <link>http://josef.spjut.me/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on Josef Spjut</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Josef Spjut</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 22:00:24 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://josef.spjut.me/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaming Toxicity for Developers</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/post/2019/gaming-toxicity-for-devs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 22:00:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/post/2019/gaming-toxicity-for-devs/</guid>
      <description>Toxicity is a huge problem in online video games. Some of the most well-known toxic online gaming communities include League of Legends, Dota and your favorite console shooters. While console shooters have generally included voice chat and a range of &amp;ldquo;your mom&amp;rdquo; insults screamed by the 13 year olds on the other end of the line, PC games typically include text chat, and a clearly visible record of every toxic statement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Console to PC Game Port Requests</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/post/2019/console-to-pc-port/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 16:51:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/post/2019/console-to-pc-port/</guid>
      <description>Over the holiday break, I had a chance to play a number of different games. Among these games, I tried out a few PC ports of primarily console-focused games, and I was reminded of some things that frustrate me when I have my &amp;ldquo;PC Gamer&amp;rdquo; hat on. Without calling out any particular developer or publisher, I&amp;rsquo;d like to take this change to suggest a few recommendations for PC ports that I wish every developer would follow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jetson TK1 First Steps</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2014/05/20/jetson-tk1-first-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2014/05/20/jetson-tk1-first-steps/</guid>
      <description>I recently received my Jetson TK1 Development Board, which I&amp;rsquo;m evaluating for potential use in an embedded systems course next Spring. This board is attractive to me because it has a high-end quad core ARM A15 processor as well as a high-end mobile GPU with support for the latest OpenGL and CUDA development environments. This post is going to serve as a way for me to record the things needed to set up the device in the first place, and hopefully more posts will follow as I manage to develop some examples on the board that will hopefully turn into lab assignments for the class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPhone 5S Release</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/technology/2013/09/20/iphone-5s-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/technology/2013/09/20/iphone-5s-release/</guid>
      <description>I bought my first iPhone 2 years ago in October of 2011. I got the 5th iPhone then, the one called the iPhone 4S (or force for short). Two years have passed and I was eligible for a subsidized upgrade on the 7th iPhone, which they call iPhone 5S (is that SS or 55?). I decided I wanted to get the new upgrade, so I went ahead and ordered one online just after midnight when they went on sale.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>