<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on Josef Spjut</title>
    <link>http://josef.spjut.me/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on Josef Spjut</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Josef Spjut</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 08:24:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://josef.spjut.me/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>G3D Starter Project</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/post/2018/g3d-starter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 08:24:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/post/2018/g3d-starter/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been spending a lot of my time working on projects based on the G3D Innovation Engine by Morgan McGuire. I personally learned how to program using unix development tools, so I&amp;rsquo;m used to using the command line for everything, and Makefiles are the build tool I&amp;rsquo;m most comfortable with. G3D, being a research game engine, primarily for graphics research, has had to focus on Windows-based development for a number of years now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phaser Game</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/post/2017/phaser-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 15:14:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/post/2017/phaser-game/</guid>
      <description>In the past few weeks, I decided to spend some of my spare time trying out some new methods for game development. In particular, I thought it would be good to come up with something that would allow me to easily create a networked game for multiple players, and would give me a chance to learn something new. I decided to look into javascript frameworks, and there were a wide variety out there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animated GIFs from Movies</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2014/01/25/animated-gifs-from-movies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2014/01/25/animated-gifs-from-movies/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve often wanted to be able to make animated gifs of things. I have also been interested in simple programmatic video editing from time to time, particularly for animating a series of still frames from images rendered by my graphics architecture simulations. Today on reddit, I came across this blog post that describes a sequence of ways to use the MoviePy library to generate animated gifs. It looks like exactly the kind of solution I want since I like to use python whenever possible for simple things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easiest Development Job Ever</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2013/09/25/easiest-development-job-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2013/09/25/easiest-development-job-ever/</guid>
      <description>Today I came across a blog post from a developer who describes a project he worked on that failed spectacularly. This project was a web database query to sort real estate brokers for an insurance company. If you want to see the results of the project in the way the original author intended, then you should visit the link above. It turns out that the insurance company provides the contact info of real estate brokers solely to collect a referral fee for that service.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>