<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Graphics on Josef Spjut</title>
    <link>http://josef.spjut.me/tags/graphics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Graphics on Josef Spjut</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Josef Spjut</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/graphics/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Jetson TK1 First Steps</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2014/05/20/jetson-tk1-first-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2014/05/20/jetson-tk1-first-steps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently received my &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.nvidia.com/jetson-tk1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jetson TK1 Development
Board&lt;/a&gt;, which I&amp;rsquo;m evaluating
for potential use in an embedded systems course next Spring.
This board is attractive to me because it has a high-end quad core ARM
A15 processor as well as a high-end mobile GPU with support for the
latest OpenGL and CUDA development environments.
This post is going to serve as a way for me to record the things
needed to set up the device in the first place, and hopefully more
posts will follow as I manage to develop some examples on the board
that will hopefully turn into lab assignments for the class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you notice when you plug in the board and turn it on,
is that it boots to an OS without any setup because the built-in flash
has linux on it from the factory.
However, there is no x11 support out of the box.
Well that&amp;rsquo;s not quite true&amp;hellip;
The support is available, but you must &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.download.nvidia.com/embedded/jetson/TK1/README.txt&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;run a script to install the
driver&lt;/a&gt;.
The instructions from the README are copied and inline here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This README file lists instructions on how to install the NVIDIA
Linux driver binary release on your target located in:
${HOME}/NVIDIA-INSTALLER

Step 1)
Change directories into the NVIDIA installation directory:
    cd ${HOME}/NVIDIA-INSTALLER

Step 2)
Run the installer script to extract and install the Linux driver
binary release:
    sudo ./installer.sh

Step 3)
Reboot the system to have the graphical desktop UI come up.

NOTES:
- The installer.sh should only be run once.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More to come&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NVIDIA GameWorks</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/graphics/2013/10/18/nvidia-gameworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/graphics/2013/10/18/nvidia-gameworks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gearnuke.com/nvidia-announces-gameworks-program-montreal-2013-supports-steamos/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;NVIDIA announced&lt;/a&gt;
a new program to help game developers
effectively use NVIDIA hardware called GameWorks.
The thing that excites me the most about GameWorks is the inclusion of
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nvidia.com/object/optix.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Optix&lt;/a&gt; in a program that
directly targets game developers.
Optix is a ray tracing environment developed by people I know from my
studies at Utah that has previously been used to help develop
rendering engines for design and production environments.
This recent announcement means that the important global illumination
features that work more naturally in ray tracing will be more readily
available for game developers.
I expect it will still be a couple of years before any top games are
released using ray tracing in the real time rendering engine, but this
represents a clear step in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also today, &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/2013/10/17/twimtbp/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;NVIDIA announced game bundles&lt;/a&gt;
and $50-$100 discounts to the SHIELD handheld game system for people
who also purchase a Geforce GTX graphics card.
Finally, a new technology called
&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/2013/10/18/g-sync/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;G-SYNC&lt;/a&gt; was
announced that allows the GPU to refresh the monitor at a variable
refresh rate, more closely tying the visuals coming from your display
to the underlying game engine.
Oh, and one more interesting note, NVIDIA also expressed direct
interest in supporting SteamOS when it launches, indicating that Linux
graphics drivers should continue to be a priority for the company.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
