<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Graphics on Josef Spjut</title>
    <link>http://josef.spjut.me/tags/graphics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Graphics on Josef Spjut</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Josef Spjut</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://josef.spjut.me/tags/graphics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Jetson TK1 First Steps</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2014/05/20/jetson-tk1-first-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2014/05/20/jetson-tk1-first-steps/</guid>
      <description>I recently received my Jetson TK1 Development Board, which I&amp;rsquo;m evaluating for potential use in an embedded systems course next Spring. This board is attractive to me because it has a high-end quad core ARM A15 processor as well as a high-end mobile GPU with support for the latest OpenGL and CUDA development environments. This post is going to serve as a way for me to record the things needed to set up the device in the first place, and hopefully more posts will follow as I manage to develop some examples on the board that will hopefully turn into lab assignments for the class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NVIDIA GameWorks</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/graphics/2013/10/18/nvidia-gameworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/graphics/2013/10/18/nvidia-gameworks/</guid>
      <description>Today, NVIDIA announced a new program to help game developers effectively use NVIDIA hardware called GameWorks. The thing that excites me the most about GameWorks is the inclusion of Optix in a program that directly targets game developers. Optix is a ray tracing environment developed by people I know from my studies at Utah that has previously been used to help develop rendering engines for design and production environments. This recent announcement means that the important global illumination features that work more naturally in ray tracing will be more readily available for game developers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>