<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Josef Spjut</title>
    <link>http://josef.spjut.me/categories/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Josef Spjut</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Josef Spjut</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/categories/personal/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Thoughts</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/personal/2013/10/07/some-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/personal/2013/10/07/some-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend I got a chance to spend some time thinking about life and
a variety of concerns.
My church has a &lt;em&gt;General Conference&lt;/em&gt; every 6 months and this last
weekend was one such conference.
During these conferences the church leaders share their thoughts and
give direction and guidance to help people to live better lives where
they can contribute more to the church and society at large.
As the weekend went on, I shared a couple of quotes from the
procedings that stood out to me on my twitter account.
In particular the following quote really stood out to me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Remember, a teacher is also
a student.&amp;quot; &lt;a
href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23ldsconf&amp;amp;src=hash&#34;&gt;#ldsconf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash;
Josef (@josefspjut) &lt;a
href=&#34;https://twitter.com/josefspjut/statuses/386956946294583296&#34;&gt;October
6, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve lived by this idea for much of my life, and more recently I&amp;rsquo;ve
become even more interested in its implications.
In my teaching, I&amp;rsquo;ve tended to do my best to instill in students a
desire to teach those around them and to thoroughly understand
material as a result.
I know I&amp;rsquo;ve found that I best understand material when I&amp;rsquo;m able to
teach that to others.
In fact, I&amp;rsquo;ve gained a much greater understanding of digital
electronics, embedded systems, and computer architecture as a result
of the classes I&amp;rsquo;ve taught in the last year.
I may have gained more from teaching than any individual student
gained from taking the class.
While the initial intent of the above quote concerned the sharing of
spiritual knowledge, I personally believe all truth should be shared
in a similar fashion.
The &lt;em&gt;teacher&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;student&lt;/em&gt; should both be learning and growing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
