<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Josef Spjut</title>
    <link>http://josef.spjut.me/tags/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Josef Spjut</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Josef Spjut</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 09:49:57 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://josef.spjut.me/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Notes</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/post/2017/hugo-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 09:49:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/post/2017/hugo-notes/</guid>
      <description>I recently undertook the effort of moving my website from jekyll using jekyll-bootstrap to Hugo and I wanted to record some notes from my efforts. In particular I want to collect a set of useful links that helped me in making the switch.
For what it&amp;rsquo;s worth, I greatly prefer Hugo now that I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten used to it, though there wasn&amp;rsquo;t too much broken about Jekyll.
The most useful thing for developing my site was when I found the academic theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Submitting my first article to arXiv</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/research/2014/12/02/submitting-my-first-article-to-arxiv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/research/2014/12/02/submitting-my-first-article-to-arxiv/</guid>
      <description>Today I submitted a technical report done by my students over the last academic year. It took a while to get the write-up to the level of quality that I felt good about submitting it, but now that it&amp;rsquo;s there, I figured I should push it out. I used arXiv to post it since they make it easy to publish a technical report while not preventing you from submitting the work to another venue such as a conference or journal at a later date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jetson TK1 First Steps</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2014/05/20/jetson-tk1-first-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/programming/2014/05/20/jetson-tk1-first-steps/</guid>
      <description>I recently received my Jetson TK1 Development Board, which I&amp;rsquo;m evaluating for potential use in an embedded systems course next Spring. This board is attractive to me because it has a high-end quad core ARM A15 processor as well as a high-end mobile GPU with support for the latest OpenGL and CUDA development environments. This post is going to serve as a way for me to record the things needed to set up the device in the first place, and hopefully more posts will follow as I manage to develop some examples on the board that will hopefully turn into lab assignments for the class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Busy Semester</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/teaching/2014/04/16/a-busy-semester/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/teaching/2014/04/16/a-busy-semester/</guid>
      <description>This semester has been extremely exciting. In particular, E85 has been updated from MIPS to use the ARM v7 instructions set. This has been a good experience for me despite some difficulties and a few moments of intensity where I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure things would come together in time. In doing this, I&amp;rsquo;ve come to learn a lot about the ARM ISA, and I&amp;rsquo;ve decided I like it a lot. In particular, I think it strikes a reasonably good balance between RISC and CISC instructions where there are a couple nice addressing modes for stack manipulation that aren&amp;rsquo;t quite RISC, but are close enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jekyll Bootstrap: rake post</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/website/2013/09/18/jekyll-bootstrap-rake-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/website/2013/09/18/jekyll-bootstrap-rake-post/</guid>
      <description>I recently discovered a new feature that comes with Jekyll bootstrap, but I&amp;rsquo;m unsure whether it is only in JB, or if it comes by default with Jekyll. There is a Rakefile (which is sort of like a Makefile, but written in Ruby) that includes a few nice functions. The one I discovered most recently allows you to create a new blog post complete with the YAML frontmatter and the proper file name for Jekyll to do the right thing with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year, New Website</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/website/2013/09/01/new-year-new-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/website/2013/09/01/new-year-new-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I happened across [jekyll-bootstrap][] the other day, and I decided I
should move my website to &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;github.io&lt;/a&gt; after seeing
what &lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;jekyll&lt;/a&gt; can do.
Among my favorite features are the ability to use markdown for web
pages, which allows a reasonably good citation syntax for adding links
to my co-authors.
As an example, the following is the syntax for one paper along with
the citations to my co-authors:
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>