<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Game Design on Josef Spjut</title>
    <link>http://josef.spjut.me/tags/game-design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Game Design on Josef Spjut</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Josef Spjut</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 16:51:24 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://josef.spjut.me/tags/game-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Console to PC Game Port Requests</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/post/2019/console-to-pc-port/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 16:51:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/post/2019/console-to-pc-port/</guid>
      <description>Over the holiday break, I had a chance to play a number of different games. Among these games, I tried out a few PC ports of primarily console-focused games, and I was reminded of some things that frustrate me when I have my &amp;ldquo;PC Gamer&amp;rdquo; hat on. Without calling out any particular developer or publisher, I&amp;rsquo;d like to take this change to suggest a few recommendations for PC ports that I wish every developer would follow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phaser Game</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/post/2017/phaser-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 15:14:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/post/2017/phaser-game/</guid>
      <description>In the past few weeks, I decided to spend some of my spare time trying out some new methods for game development. In particular, I thought it would be good to come up with something that would allow me to easily create a networked game for multiple players, and would give me a chance to learn something new. I decided to look into javascript frameworks, and there were a wide variety out there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Design Thoughts</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/game-design/2014/01/14/game-design-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/game-design/2014/01/14/game-design-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking recently about the kinds of things I&amp;rsquo;d like to work on most during the break from teaching, and I&amp;rsquo;ve decided that I really want to take a deep look at game design from a theoretical and practical standpoint. It seems to me that there could be some need for a more formal and methodological approach to the design of games than currently exists. In my experience, game designers (the ones that put the fun into the game) are hard to find and extremely hard to train.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>