<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Josef Spjut</title>
    <link>http://josef.spjut.me/categories/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Josef Spjut</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Josef Spjut</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 08:24:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://josef.spjut.me/categories/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AR Research 2015-2018</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/post/2018/ar-research-2015-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 08:24:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/post/2018/ar-research-2015-2018/</guid>
      <description>Since 2015, I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on a variety of research projects that I&amp;rsquo;d retrospectively say were all related to the future of augmented reality, and particularly head mounted displays for augmented reality. I&amp;rsquo;ve recently started shifting my research focus to a new area, so I figured this would be a good time to post a retrospective of what I&amp;rsquo;ve done and what I feel I&amp;rsquo;ve learned over these last 3 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Submitting my first article to arXiv</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/research/2014/12/02/submitting-my-first-article-to-arxiv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/research/2014/12/02/submitting-my-first-article-to-arxiv/</guid>
      <description>Today I submitted a technical report done by my students over the last academic year. It took a while to get the write-up to the level of quality that I felt good about submitting it, but now that it&amp;rsquo;s there, I figured I should push it out. I used arXiv to post it since they make it easy to publish a technical report while not preventing you from submitting the work to another venue such as a conference or journal at a later date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undergraduate Research</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/research/2013/09/19/undergraduated-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/research/2013/09/19/undergraduated-research/</guid>
      <description>Over the last year, I advised 5 undergraduate students on a couple research projects. One of them included the development of tutorials and lab assignments for a new class, but didn&amp;rsquo;t have a goal of publishing an academic paper. This student did a good job, and added on a persistance of vision display to a combat robot&amp;rsquo;s spinning arm that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have otherwise been there.
The other main project involved the rest of my research students.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>