<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Confidence on Josef Spjut</title>
    <link>http://josef.spjut.me/tags/confidence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Confidence on Josef Spjut</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Josef Spjut</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/confidence/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Embedded Design</title>
      <link>http://josef.spjut.me/teaching/2013/09/17/embedded-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josef.spjut.me/teaching/2013/09/17/embedded-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week I met with each of the students in my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www3.hmc.edu/~jspjut/class/e155&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MicroPs&lt;/a&gt; class
and discussed their lab assignment.
The first lab assignment was primarily soldering components onto their
PCB and verifying that all of the components worked.
As part of these lab interviews, I get to ask each student a question
about their project to try to test their knowledge.
One thing I noticed is that many of the students didn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;own&lt;/em&gt; their
project as fully as I would like.
What I mean by that is that when I would ask what a button on their
board does, then would respond by asking me if it does what they think
it does.
This is a very student sort of behavior, and I&amp;rsquo;d really like to teach
them to be more confident and assertive in what they turn in.
Today, I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell the class that they should not answer my lab
interview questions with another question, but instead respond with
confidence according to their best knowledge.
Of course if you don&amp;rsquo;t know the answer, you really shouldn&amp;rsquo;t say
something as if it&amp;rsquo;s true, but the right way to respond in that case
is with full honesty that you don&amp;rsquo;t know the answer, but you suspect
or believe it works this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you design something, you should &lt;em&gt;own that design&lt;/em&gt;. That is all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
